New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Digital Photographs 6202 P(d)
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Digital Photographs
1970-2005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)
New York State AFL-CIO
Cole, Paul
6202 P(d)
3.41 Gigabytes
115 TIF files and 115 JPG files
Digital images.
8255166
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 12, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 04, 2016
Biographical / Historical
David Lawrence Cole was a graduate of Harvard University (BS., 1921) and Fairleigh Dickinson University (LL.B., 1924, LL.D., 1964.) Although he practiced law in Paterson, N.J. from 1926 until his death as senior partner in the law firm of Cole, Berman & Belksy, David Cole will chiefly be remembered for a distinguished career as a government arbitrator and mediator. In this field he served on numerous state and federal boards and in various governmental agencies. Cole was chairman of the New Jersey State Board of Mediation; a public member of Region 2, United States War Labor Board; and chairman of the Presidential Boards of Inquiry in the bituminous coal industry (1948) and in the longshore industry (1953, 1968). Cole was also a member or chairman of numerous Presidential Emergency Boards which settled disputes in the railroad and airline industries (1948-1958); the chairman of the conciliation service for the New York City transit service (1961-1965); director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (1952-1953); chairman of the New Jersey Governor's Committee on Public Utility Strike Service (1952-1953); member of the President's Labor-Management Advisory Committee (1961-1964); and member of the New York Governor's Public Employee Relations Committee (1966-1968), which established the New York State Public Employee Relations Board. Cole was also appointed as chairman of the President's Commission on Industrial Peace in 1973.
Beyond his public service, Mr. Cole was active as a counsel for employer groups in the textile industry (1926-1942) and as an impartial chairman for other labor-management contract disputes. He was also impartial arbitrator for the AFL-CIO Internal Disputes Plan (1954-1976), served as a visiting professor at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University (1954-1955) and was Kestenbaum lecturer at Harvard in 1962. Mr. Cole was the author of INDUSTRIAL PEACE (1963).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6202: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Files 6202 AV: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Audio-Visual Materials 6202 OH: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Oral History on Minidiscs 6203: New York State AFL-CIO Director Al Davidoff Files
Cole, Paul; New York State AFL-CIO; AFL-CIO
8255166
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, and others with NY plaque (Box 1, Folder 1a)
  Scope and Contents
  Size: 9.5"x7.5"
- Paul Cole and Ezra Cornell in scholarly robes (Box 1, Folder 1b)
  Size: 5"x7"
- ILR dedication March 9, 1998 Paul Cole, Dave Lipsky, Ed Cleary (Box 1, Folder 1c)
  Size: 5"x3.5"
- ILR dedication March 9, 1998 Paul Cole and Hunter Rawlings (Box 1, Folder 1d)
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, ILR faculty take a stroll (Box 1, Folder 1e)
- Paul Cole and Ed Cleary at ILR construction site (Box 1, Folder 1f)
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary and others at ILR construction site (Box 1, Folder 1g)
- Cole, Cleary, Lipsky and others cut 50th anniversary cake (Box 1, Folder 1h)
- Cole, Cleary and [unknown] at Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 1i)
- ILO meeting Geneva, June 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
  Size: 4"x6"
- Paul Cole wearing bifocals, speaking (Box 1, Folder 2b)
  Size: 6"x4"
- Paul Cole at meeting of Education International in Harare, Zimbabwe (Box 1, Folder 2c)
- ILO meeting June 2000, Geneva (Box 1, Folder 2d)
- ILR dedication March 9, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2e)
- Paul Cole casting vote as member of electoral college Albany, January 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2f)
- Paul Cole speaking at 4th world congress 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2g)
  Size: 8"x6"
- Paul Cole speaking at NY AFL-CIO (Box 1, Folder 2h)
- Paul Cole speaking Meeting the Challenges 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2i)
- Paul Cole speaking under trees (Box 1, Folder 2j)
  Size: 6.5"x4.5"
- Close-up of Paul Cole speaking on steps (Box 1, Folder 2k)
- Paul Cole speaking on steps (Box 1, Folder 2l)
- Paul Cole speaking to university audience (Box 1, Folder 2m)
- Paul Cole with microphone (Box 1, Folder 2n)
  Size: 9.7"x7.7"
- Paul Cole, Secretary Treasurer NYS AFL-CIO at the podium, New York City Central Labor Council AFL-CIO 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3a)
- Paul Cole, Lane Kirkland, Ed Cleary, 1985 (small loss in image center) (Box 1, Folder 3b)
  Size: 8" x 10"
- Tom Donohue, Ed Cleary and Paul Cole display State AFL-CIO license plate (Box 1, Folder 3c)
- Danny Donohue, Paul Cole and Alan [Labin? Fabin, Fahi??] and Denis Hughes talking (Box 1, Folder 3d)
- Paul Cole, [unknown, unknown] and Ed Cleary at a speakers table (Box 1, Folder 3e)
- New York State AFL-CIO 28th Constitutional Convention includes Paul Cole, Ed Cleary at the central podium and many others standing and seated on the stage. (Box 1, Folder 3f)
- New York State AFL-CIO 28th Constitutional Convention. Paul Cole and Ed Cleary with hands held high together (Box 1, Folder 3g)
- Paul Cole, Denis Hughes, Ed Cleary and [unknown]. Cleary passes the gavel to Hughes (Box 1, Folder 3h)
- New York State AFL-CIO headquarters building and annex in Albany (Box 1, Folder 3i)
  Size: 4 x 5.5"
- Denis Hughes and Paul Cole at the podium, gripped hands raised while onlookers applaud. (Box 1, Folder 3j)
  Size: 5x7"
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, and Denis Hughes walk between 2 rows of Scottish pipers [ca. 2000] (Box 1, Folder 3k)
- Paul and Lynne Cole, Maureen and Denis Hughes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3l)
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, and Denis Hughes at the dedication of 100 S. Swan Street [Albany] as the Edward J. Cleary Building, March 1999. (Box 1, Folder 3m)
- President Sweeny swears in Denis Hughes as State AFL-CIO President, March 1999. Ed Cleary and Paul Cole look on. (Box 1, Folder 3n)
- Paul Cole and Sean Connolly, great-grandson of James Connolly in Ireland at Teachers Union of Ireland, Dublin Teachers Union office (Box 1, Folder 4a)
  Size: 3x5"
- Paul Cole, center, member, with National Park Service Advisory Board at meeting at Rocky Mountain National Park, August, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4b)
  Size: 4x6"
- Lynne and Paul Cole and 1996 Democratic Convention holding Gore and Clinton banners. (Box 1, Folder 4c)
- Paul Cole and Pat [Hepping] (CA) in dirty white coveralls and hard hats following a tour of [Oberhausen] Germany coal mine, 1970s, 1970- 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4d)
- Paul Cole with children [in bush village near] Harare Zimbabwe during Educational International Congress (Box 1, Folder 4e)
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, [unknown], Joe Faberty, John Sweeney, Joe Jamison, Tom Donahue at the 1994 100th Anniversary of the Irish Congress of Trade Union parade with IBEW Local 3 Sword and Light [pipe and drum] Band (Box 1, Folder 4f)
- Herb Magidson, Paul Cole, Barbara Magidson and Lynne Cole at a retirement party for NYSUT Secretary Treasurer Herb Magidson March 1994 (Magidson is also Vice President of the AFT) (Box 1, Folder 4g)
- Paul Cole, Gary Duesberg (State AFL-CIO Education Director), and Jeff Arnett (Baseball Hall of Fame Education Director) (Box 1, Folder 4h)
- Paul Cole and AFT as election observer delegation for Chilean plebiscite. Osnoldo Verdiego, President of Chile Teachers is front row, 4th from left. (Box 1, Folder 4i)
- Secretary of Labor Robert Reich and Secretary of Education Riley with Paul Cole and the National Skills Standard Board, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4j)
  Size: 8x10"
- Paul Cole wearing the Ellis Island Medal of Honor at a celebration in NY City, 2000 with his family (Box 1, Folder 4k)
- Paul Cole and others at the US Army War College, National Security Seminar, June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4l)
- Paul Cole and others at the US Army War College, National Security Seminar, June 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4m)
  Size: 8x4.5"
- Paul Cole at meeting with the League of Public School Teachers, Beirut, Lebanon, April 2005 including [Youssef Elias Moukaryel, Ez Moursil Assad Al Haddad, Audra George, Antoine Milad, Hannah Ibrahim Gharib, and Larry Specht.] (Box 1, Folder 4n)
- Tom Hobart, Paul Cole, Dick [Ianuzzi] at EI Congress in Brazil, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4o)
- Richard [Ianuzzi], Tom Hobart and Paul Cole at Iguazzu Falls, Brazil (Box 1, Folder 4p)
- AFT Convention in Ohio (Box 1, Folder 4q)
  Size: 8x12"
- Paul Cole and Daniel Patrick Moynihan (Box 1, Folder 5a)
  Photographer: Unknown. Size: 6.5x4.5"
- Toni Cortese, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Tom Hobart, Paul Cole, Lynne Cole (Box 1, Folder 5b)
  Photographer: Images Unlimited. Size: 9.5x6.5"
- Paul Cole and Ted Kennedy. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5c)
  Size: 8x6"
- Paul Cole, Lynne Cole, Ted Kennedy. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5d)
  Size: 7.7x7"
- Paul Cole with Michael Dukakis. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5e)
- Paul Cole with Mario Cuervo. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5f)
- AFT Executive Council meeting. Paul Cole, Lynne Cole, Senator Chris Dodd. Florida. February, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5g)
  Size: 5.7x4"
- Paul Cole with Chief Justice Warren Burger (Box 1, Folder 5h)
  Size: 4.8x6"
- Paul Cole with Secretary of Education Richard Riley (Box 1, Folder 5i)
  Size: 6.5x4.5"
- Paul Cole, Lynne Cole, Senator Tom Harkin. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5j)
- Paul Cole with Geraldine Ferrari, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5k)
- Paul Cole with Sheldon Silver, Dennis Hughes, and another man (Box 1, Folder 5l)
- Assemblyman Michael Bragman, Assembly speaker Sheldon Silver, Assemblywoman Catherine Nolan, Assemblyman Denny Farrell, Ed Cleary, Paul Cole (Box 1, Folder 5m)
- Congressman Sam Stratton, Ed Cleary, Congressman Henry [Nowak] Congressman Stan Lundine, and Paul Cole (Box 1, Folder 5n)
  Photographer: unknown. Size: 8.5x6.6"
- Paul Cole, Sheldon Silver, Alan Lubin (Box 1, Folder 5o)
- Paul Cole with Mary Robinson, president of Ireland. 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5p)
- Congressman Gerald Solomon, Paul Cole, Congressman Tom Manton (Box 1, Folder 5q)
- Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, Labor Chair Frank Barbaro (Box 1, Folder 5r)
- Paul Cole, Congressman John LaFalce, Emily Cole (Box 1, Folder 5s)
- Paul Cole with Dick Gebhardt (Box 1, Folder 5t)
  Size: 4.8x3.4"
- Paul Cole. Introduction of John Kerry at Queens Community College. September, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5u)
  Size: 9.9x6.8"
- Paul Cole with Senator John Kerry (Box 1, Folder 5v)
- Paul Cole with Bill Clinton with blue background. October, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5w)
- President Clinton greets Paul Cole and Lynne Cole at White House Reception, December 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5x)
  Size: 7.8x5.5"
- Paul Cole shakes hands with Bill Clinton (Box 1, Folder 5y)
  Size: 9.4x6.2"
- Al Gore, Paul Cole, Brian McLaughlin (Box 1, Folder 5z)
  Size: 4.9x3.5"
- Paul Cole shakes hands with Al Gore (Box 1, Folder 6a)
  Size: 9.7x6.3"
- Paul Cole, Governor Pataki, Dennis Hughes, Labor Commisioner Linda Angello (Box 1, Folder 6b)
- Paul Cole and [unknown] (Box 1, Folder 6c)
- Paul Cole with 2 others (Box 1, Folder 6d)
  Size: 6x4"
- Paul Cole with Senator Shumer (Box 1, Folder 6e)
- Paul Cole, Hillary Clinton and Denis Hughes (Box 1, Folder 6f)
- [no title] (Box 1, Folder 6g)
- Hilary Clinton speaking at New York State AFL-CIO, Paul Cole looks on (Box 1, Folder 6h)
- Josephine Le Beau [unknown], [unknown], Hillary Clinton, Paul Cole and Denis Hughes. (Box 1, Folder 6i)
  Photographer: Miller Photography, 1300 Jericho Turnpike, New Hyde Park, NY 11040. Size: 6.5x4.5"
- Denis Hughes, Paul Cole and Hillary Clinton (Box 1, Folder 6j)
  Size: 6x8"
- Paul Cole with Labor Secretary Alexis Herman (Box 1, Folder 6k)
- Paul Cole with Senator Pat Moynihan. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6l)
- Paul Cole, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, and Ed Clearly at NYS AFL-CIO 28th Constitutional Convention (Box 1, Folder 6m)
- Paul Cole with Dick Gephardt (Box 1, Folder 6n)
  Size: 5.8x4"
- Paul Cole, Lynne Cole, Gerry Adams (Box 1, Folder 6o)
- Tom Fricano of United Auto Workers Region 9, Paul Cole, Ed Cleary, Jim Molloy doorkeeper of House of representatives, Dennis Hughes (Box 1, Folder 6p)
  Size: 8.6x6.6"
- Paul Cole and Lynne Cole at Clinton Inauguration. January, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6q)
  Size: 3.8x5.8"
- Paul Cole with Tipper Gore, March 23, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6r)
  Size: 4.5x5.5"
- Paul Cole, Ed Bavarello, Mayor David Dinkins. NYC, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6s)
- Paul Cole, Ambassador to Ireland, Jean Kennedy Smith, Lynne Cole at 100th Anniversary of Congress of Trade Unions in Dublin, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6t)
- Prime Minister Albert Reynolds and Paul Cole at 100th Anniversary of ICTU in Dublin. May, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6u)
- Lynne Cole, Lord Mayor of Dublin, Paul Cole at 100th Anniversary of ICTU, Dublin. May 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6v)
- White House Reception for AFL. Madelin Kerwin, Paul Cole, Secretary of Education Richard Riley (Box 1, Folder 6w)
- Paul Cole, NY labor commissioner Linda Angello, CSEA president Danny Donohue (Box 1, Folder 6x)
- Paul Cole, Lynne Cole, Cardinal OConnor. Labor Day, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6y)
- Sunny Hure, Paul Cole, Denny Farrell, Ed Cleary, Jim Kerr (Box 1, Folder 6z)
  Size: 9.5x7.4"
- Paul Cole with Walter Mondale, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7a)
  Size: 6.8x5"
- Paul Cole, Lech Walesa, and Herb Magidson (Box 1, Folder 7b)
- Tom Hobart, John Sweeney, Sandra Feldman, Al Gore, Paul Cole, Ad McElroy (Box 1, Folder 7c)
- Gary Hart, Rachelle Horowitz (AFT political director), Paul Cole. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7d)
  Size: 9.5x6.3"
- Tom Hobart, Lin Ullman, Toni Cortese, Nat LaCour, Paul Cole (Box 1, Folder 7e)
  Size: 9.5x6.9"
- Paul Cole, Labor Secretary Bill Brock, SCANS Commission Certificate (Box 1, Folder 7f)
- Paul Cole and Al Gore at 1996 Democratic National Convention (Box 1, Folder 7g)
  Size: 6.6x4.6"
- Paul Cole with Dick Gephardt (Box 1, Folder 7h)
  Size: 6.3x5"
- Paul Cole in purple suit reading newspaper with Congressman Gerald Solomon (Box 1, Folder 7i)
  Size: 7.4x4.9"